Connecticut Citizens Action Group Records 1987.0024
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
- Series XX: 2013 Addition, 1990-2010
  - Manuscripts,Correspondence, 1990-2010 (Box 2013.0157_6)
    [Subjects Include] 1999, 1998,1997,Current Issues, Filing, Environment, 1991 Legislative Agenda, Environment, Endorsement Resolution, Legislative Electoral Program, Annual Report 2002, LEAD grants genral info,Grant list and flow chart, "Citizens Guide To Hazardous Wastes" by Bette Bono, Field Canvass Payroll, Incinerators, Articles, Insurance,1989 Leg. Achievments, CCAG Board Meeting, CCAG Research Group, CCRG Board Meeting,Issue Originals, 1991 Legislative Agenda, 2003 program Literature and Flyers, Global Warming Flyers, Auto Insurance, CCRG Board Meeting, 2003 "The Drive for Cleaner Air in Connecticut", Color of Money 2003, "Sources of Progressive themes in Culture and History" Book, 2003 Program Literature and flyers, "Not in Anyones Backyard A Citizens Guide To Hazardous Wastes" by Bette Bono with Rebecca Doty, Trash Burining is halted news article, Research Group Board Meeting, Research Group budjet plans, Field canvas payroll, grant lists and flow charts, Connecticut Citizens Research Group Financial statements, Letters to The Arca Foundation, Hot Tomatoes Resturant, Pound House Cafe, Woodland Pizza, Woldes Ethiopian Restaurant, "Bad Policy Bad Medicine by Robert S. Mclntyre and Wendy J. Ray, Surveys, Web print outs
  - Fliers, Manuscrpits ,Correspondence, 1990-2010 (Box 2013.0157_7)
    [Subjects Include]: 1993 Connecticut Research Group, Connecticut Research Group Gambling and the AD Book Exemption, Flyers On lead poisoning, Connecticut Research Group Meeting Documents, Press, Flyers on Connecticut Tobbaco Tax, Flyers on Voter Owned Elections, Campaign access committee, Flyers for consumer health action, " Campaign Finance Reform", Testimony of Michael Jordan, Letter to senator Dodd, Flyer regarding Congress Privatizing Medicare, News Article "Senators cruise daws protestors", Photo of protestors, Peter D. Hart Research Associates, Flyers regarding voting for Ed Gomes, Testimony of Tom Swan Government Administration and Elections Committee, Connecticut Action Group Press release, Flyer regarding voting for Joe Courtney, Flyer Regarding a Rally and March Against the Privatization of Medicare Destrcution of Medicaid and Rowlands Health Care Cuts, Flyer regarding Legislative Update on Healthcare Issues 2001, Dirty Money an analysis of campaign contributions and environmental enforcements by Eric Bailey, Financial reports for the Budget, Board Minutes, congress for connecticut futures, Research Groups Contract, Agreement between International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America and its Local 376 and Connecticut Action Group,Letter to George Reider, State of Connecticut Insurance Department,Blue Cross Blue Shield Insuranceg, "Campaign Finance Reform & Faith" Book, Consumers Union, Erisa Info, Managed Care, Health Care, Model, Annual Report of the Interfaith Center on Corporate Responsibility, Agenda, Sun Health Group, 1995 Retreat,
  - Manuscripts, 1990-2010 (Box 2013.0157_8)
    [Subjects Include]:Campaign Finance Working Group, Mass voters For Clean Elections, Captial Eye, Center for a New Democracy's Update on Campaign Finance Reform, Memorandum to the National Governing Board, Northeast Citizens Action Resource Center, Connecticut Moneuy and Politics Project, Money and Politics In New Hampshire, "Speaking Freely "by Martin Schram, National Voters Rights Institute, Voters Pamphlet,Democracy, "Coming to Terms" A Money in Politics Glossary,Campaign Finance Reform-other states mid - nineties, Money In politics Research Studies, Money in Politics - where money comes from and what it buys in the world of politics, Petitions, Testimony Democracy Video, Legislative -1995, Press contacts,
  - Photographs, Video Cassette, Manuscripts, 1990-2010 (Box 2013.0157_9)
    [Subject Include]: 5 Photo Graphs, Video Cassette titled "The Road to Clean Elections" Produced by Haddow Communications, Murray Fishel Grassroots Campaign Training, Color of Money (Public Campaign), CFR LIT, "Color of Money :2003" Book, Women Speak out in support of Clean Elections, CFWG Draft Bill 2005,Field History,Community organizing project, Enviromental Health, Miscellaneous Old Raps, Transportation, C.F.R. Fast Track, Health Care Literature Perscriptions and Tabacco Tax, News Letter, Team Fat Cat Lobbyist, Media list of Numbers, Paying a Premium: The Added Cost of Care for the Uninsured, CBIA Anuual Report 2003, The Connecticut Health Advancement And Research Trust INC., Health Care Strategy Meeting January 14-16 2002, Fiald Orientation Booklet, Program Book 1999-2000, Connecticut Constitutional History, Dismantling Racism: A Resource Book, US Action Committee, Wisconsin Citizen Action, Questionnaire, State Secrets A joint investigation of political party money in the states, Blue Chip Investors The Top 100 Donors to Federal Elections 1989-2002, Anti-Bribery Action Kit ,2000 State Election Overview, Medicad and the uninsured, Campaign Clips Surface Transportation Policy Project, Campaign Update, Five Years of Progress, A Shoppers Guide to Pesticides in Produce, Toxic Empire, Flyers,Quaterly Tax Reports
  - Manuscripts, Coresspondence, Fliers, Publications, 1990-2010 (Box 2013.0157_10)
    [Subjects Include]: National Citizens Action, Connecticut Citizens Action Group National Operating Strategy, National States Citizens Action, Rowland Tax Changes, Grants Info, GREGG, Campaign Finance Video, North East Action, North East Action "Winning in 96",Tobbaco, Newspaper AD's, Written Ad for Tobacco Alliance for a Healthy Connecticut, Tobacco Prevention and Control Training, Executive Summary Four Focus Groups For Smokefree Wisconsin,AHC 2002 Planning, Tobacco Health Trust Fund, MATCH Coalition, Campaign For Tobacco Free Kids, The Capital Substance Abuse Council, Region 9A "Taking Back The Initiative", NU, Health Issues Involving Tobacco, Tobacco Ad's, Flyers for different events, "Dirty Money" An analysis of campaign contributions and environmental enforcement ,Out of Many, One: A Multicultural Action Plan to Achieve Health Parity, "The Price Of Admission: Campign Spending in the 1994 Elections"by Larry Makinson, "The Cash Constituents of Congress" by Larry Makinson, "Challenging the wealth Primary", "Making the Connection Between Politics and Issues People Care About", Cashing In Corporate Welfare for the Energy Industry :1992, Plugging In The Public a Model For Campaign Finance Disclosure By Elizabeth Hedlund and Lisa Rosenberg, 10 Myths About Money In Politics, Report on the State of Democracy, Alliance For a Healthy New England, The Price of admission by Larry Makinson, Managed Care, Campaign Finance Reform -Literature-Materials-Correspondence, Public Funding, News Articles, The Big Picture: "The Money Behind the 2000 Elections", Straight Talk 2002: Common Sense For The New Majority, Revitalizing Democracy: Clean Election Reform Shows the way forward,Center For Responsive Politics,Health Care Press 1995(Circa),
  - Manuscripts,Correspondence,Fliers, Publications, 1990-2010 (Box 2013.0157_11)
    [Subjects Include]: AHC Funding and Grant Info,Current Organization, Connecticut State Medical Society, Alliance for a Healthy New England, Connecticut Department of Public Health Youth Tobacco Survey 2000, Tobacco Lobbying Firms, Tobacco Taxes - Other States, Unions & Smoking, Alliance for a Healthy Connecticut, DME Group and Dillon, Tobacco -Match Pre-emption Campaign, Match Coalition, "Taking Care Of Business: Citizenship and the Charter of Incorporation", STED, Citizens Action Board, Arizona Citizen Action, Articles, Utilities - National Campaign, Citizens Against State Organizations, 1996 Citizens Action Meeting, Citizen Action Stategic Plan,May 1995 Citizen Action Strategy Papers, (Check Requests) Forms-R-US,
  - Manuscripts, Correspondence,Fliers,Publications, 1990-2010 (Box 2013.0157_12)
    [Subjects Include]: The Price of Admission by Larry Makinson, Power: A repossesion Manual by Greg Speeter, "Jobs & the Economy" by Cynthia Ward Geri Langlois Diane Feldman Erica Walters, Testimonies to Legislature, Reflections: Loking Back at lessons Learned, Connecticut Citizens Action Group Consumer Handbook 1997, Connecticut's Decade of Business Tax Cuts: Public Investment wit little to show for it, Electric Restructuring Consumer and Environment Issues, Directory of Former Staff 25th Anniversary Celebration, Media CCAG Mentions 2001, Media CCAG Mentions 2003, Media CCAG Mentions 2002, Media CCAG Mentions 2003, Media Connecticut Elected Official Crime, CFR Bill-Shays-Meehan,North east Action - June 2001 - oakhurst ,Events-Retreats-staff board 2001 June, Midwest Academy training,General,Board Staff Retreat 2001, Media CRRA 2002 March,Media CRRA - 2001, Media CCAG Mentions 2000, CCAG is mentioned, Media CRRA 2002 April, Federal Law and definitions, CCAG/CCRG Reports, Binder with News clippings regarding I-84, Binder that includes information on insurance and news clippings, Binder containing information on reconstructing the electricity industry, Binder containing information about connecticut Insurance,
  - Manuscripts, Correspondence, Fliers, 1990-2010 (Box 2013.0157_13)
    [Subjects Include]: The Bulletin Connecticut General Assembly, Connecticut Citizens Action Group fliers, California Pay Play Law - SB2- Passed Oct 2003, "Pay or play"a health insurance initiative, Caring for the Uninsured in Massachusetts: " What Does It Cost, Who Pays and What Would Full Coverage Add to Medical Spending", Maine - Dirigo Health, Universal- messaging, Univerasl Health Care in other countries U.S History", Medicad Reform,Chant Program Committe 2001, Chart\Purchasing Pool Feasibility Studies 2001-2002,Pal 2002, Pfizer, ConnPACE Quaterly Report 2002,CCAG Report "Citizens Win Investigation of State Dep Trash Polocies', Women and Medicare Rx Coverage, CT's Maine RX, P.A./P.D.L., PA Implementation, PBM's,Prescription Drug Reports 2000-2001, Rx Options 2000-2002, ConnPace 'A&B' Expansion Info and Factsheets ,Public Citizen & Families USA Drug (2000-2002) Reports ,Rx Over the Internet, Citizens Health Drug Discount Card 2001, DSS Rx Cost Presentations August 2001,RX Lawsuits By HMOS,Universal - Messaging, Maine -Dirigo Health, Proposals to Restructure Medicaid: How might Connecticut Fare?, Federal Proposals To Restructure Medicad: " What could they mean for connecticut?",
  - Manuscripts,Corresspondence,Fliers, 1990-2010 (Box 2013.0157_14)
    [Subjects Include]: CCAG 1997, Universal Health Care (General, Proposals, Ideology), Tax & Budget State, Lead Poisioning 2001-2002, Alliance 2002 Mailing Group Responses / Approval Expenses, Example of Items that could in an info packet / old fact sheets,Alliance Mailing, Match Literature, AHC Response to Mail Piece May 2001,AHC Press Releases & Testimony, AHC Husky Adults -People who couldy qualify,AHNE-Miscellanouse 2002, AHC/ANNE Press & Newsletters from other groups 2002, Alliance For a Healthy New England meeting agendas 2001-2002, Cigarettes Taxes in Other State, Draft Comprehensive CT State Tobacco Prevention Program, Tobacco Fact Sheet, Alliance For Healthy New England, ACS New England Tobacco Tax Summit & Campaign, AHNE Case Statement 2000-2001, AHC Facts on Uninsured & Possible Connection to Smoking
  - Mauscripts, Corresspondence, Fliers, 1990-2010 (Box 2013.0157_15)
    [Subjects Include]: CBIA Health Connections, SCHIP Premium Assistance, Wellstone Plan 2000/Kennedy 2000, Medicaid HMO Tax Credit, Medicaid Rules 2001,Budget Cuts Special Session November 2001, 2002-2003 Proposed Rowland Budget Factsheets,Summaries, Testimonies, Connecticut Health Foundation, CBIA Health Connections, Other Countries Medical Systems, Husky Working Group 2001-2002,Buy In- Medicare/Medicaid, Medical Savings Account, Families USA Strange Bedfellows Proposal 200-2001,Families USA - Chronic Illness Report Release March 2001, Husky Legislation MB 6430,Number of Uninsured Adults In Connecticut, Resources and Websites, Health Money in Politics Contributions 2001,Union Disputes 2001-2002, Economic Stimulus Organizing Facts and Actions 2001-2002,Democratic Party Town Committee,Delegates Assembly November 16-18 2001, Managed Care Policy Institute 1st OMCO, Health care for All Americans ,Union Disputes,MSA's Medical Savings Account 2001-2002,Pediatric Exclusivity 2001-2002, Facts - Pet Health Insurance ,Medical Privacy, Nursing Home Staffing Reports and Advocacy, Municipal Elections 2001, Office of Managed Care, Mental Health Budget Issues 2002,Spending Cap, Poverty Campaigan ,Bush Tax Cut, NAIC,Chart Foundation -Reports
  - Manuscripts,Corresspondence,Fliers, 1990-2010 (Box 2013.0157_16)
    [Subjects Include]: Legislation Tracking Sheets 2001-2002,2004 Leg- Testimony & Summaries,Uninsecured,Gretchen Vivier, Conference Calls, HSA's, Flexible Benefit Designs Cost Sharing,Maine,MD-Uttc,Trainging Material, California HealthCare Foundation "Proceed with Caution: A Report on the Quality of Health Information on the internet, Media file 2002, Press, "The Real Cost of Living and getting Health Care in Connecticut", 2005 Legislature, Healthcare cost, Worldview Training,UHC Testimony 2006,Uninsured, Worldview and Training, Health care Cost /opinions, Maine, Training Materials,Cigarette Tax Near Clips, Grant Proposal, CCAG Tax Forms, Legislative 2006, Presentations, Leadership Training, Gretchen Updates ,Gretchen Vivier 2005
  - Binders, Manuscripts, 1985-2006 (Box 2013.0157_17)
    [Subjects include ]: Health Care Reform Advocacy training, National Mental Health Association,Healthcare for All Urgent Alert, Healthcare Victories in 2000,CCAG 2001 Legislative Agenda, Binder with all the history of health care, Binder with Auto insurance information, Unification Legislative Conference 1999 Washington D.C., Budget Proposal ,Human Service and PH Budget 2003, Carve- Outs ,Nursing Homes/CCN HR, Medicare and Disabilities, Premium Assistance, Medicaid Defense working group, Husky Brochures 2001-2002, Minnesota Case Against Bluecross Blue shield, Connecticut Budget Cap 2005, Husky Expansion High Risk Pool, 2005 Budget, Municipal Employees Health Insurance Program, State Budget 2003, Heatlh Care Economics, Medicaid, Medical Malpratice,
  - Fliers,Binders, Correspondence (Box 2013.0157_18)
    [Subjects Include]: Guidelines to Reduce Lead Dust In Homes & Apartments, Connecticut Citizen Action Group A Case Study & Critical Analysis ,State of Connecticut Goals And Benchmarks for the Year 2000 and Beyond,Envrionmental Resource Directory, Discover Total Resources, Power analysis, HealthCare training Overheads 2001-2002,Money in politics, Brochures, Goals and BenchMarks for the Year 200 and beyond, Book containing Connecticut Citizen Action Group Analysis, Book titled Preventing Lead Poisioning in Young Children, Book Tittled Guidelines to Reduce Lead Dust In Homes & Apartments,Book tittled- Discover total Resources a guide for nonprofits, Environmental Resource Directory, US Action reporting form
  - Administrative Records, 1977-2010 (Box 2013.0157_19)
    [subjects include: Instructions for Chris Job, L. Christopher Marolda, phone numbers, guides, directions, staff trainings, staff lists, CCAG report, maps, Political Action Committee limits, union contract, labor department information, Advanced Duplicating System, high donor fundraising training, autopost manual, congressional campaign records, productions, ontracts, project management, notes from staff and board retreat 6/13/98, and 12/5/98, media training, listening workshop, frame analysis, 2001 Biennial meeting, development plan 1997, board meeting minutes, supervision weekly to do lists, board labels, legislative index 1977-1990, 1999 annual meeting, Secratary of the State speakers bureau, miscellaneous notes and news clippings]
  - news clippings, administrative records, 1990-2010 (Box 2013.0157_20)
    [subjects include: news clippings from the resignation of Governor John G. Rowland, UConn, Toxic empire, drug costs, various issues of the Rowland governorship]
  - administrative records, manuscripts, 1990-2010 (Box 2013.0157_21)
    [subjects include: tax literature, Fair Share Campaign, nuclear information, CCAG newsletters, search committee, leases from previous office, original earth action campaign, unions, Progressive Power in the New Century, Organizational Development Committee, Finders' Fee Scandal, computer systems, Ned Lamont, notes, CCAG Issues Forum, Niennial Meeting 2/3/01, endorsement resolutions, HCFA dues 2002-2003, Connecticut womens' Health Campaign, lobby day 3/28/01, HCFA general meeting 5/02 and 5/01]
  - Administrative Records, 1990-2010 (Box 2013.0157_22)
    [subjects include: events and meetings 2004, neighbor labor 2004, email updates, meeting notices, pond house, small business, CFR, leadership letters and other information, universal healthcare newsletter, globalization fast track, 2002 redistricting, Northeast Legislative Association on RX drug prices, 2002 governors race, employee health security, CT state medical society, One connecticut 2002, CCAG 30th anniversary, lobby day, legislative update, US Action, timelines, LEAP, national committee, tax campaign, Husky/legal immigrants, HCFA, Childrens' Health Council, poverty campaign, federal poverty levels, media, nursing home strike 2001, PCCM bill language, Connpace waiver, office of Manacebcare Ombudsman, long-term care, ethic filings, federal privacy regulations, confidentiality state regulations, campaign to fight poverty and build economic security, cancer, HIV, LEAD, self sufficiency standard, campaign finance reform, medicaid, malpractice, healthcare, budget fight, voter fraud, auto insurance, CEO]
  - Administrative records, publications, 1990-2010 (Box 2013.0157_23)
    [subjects include: tobacco, environment, newspaper information, media lists, press list 1994, Democracy 2000 campaign, CEO 2000, list enhancement 2000, leadership Political Action Committee study, NAFTA, miscellaneous legislation, medical savings account, union agreement questionaire 1992, voting rights 2000, leadership for the 90s, state department receipts, CFR 2000, Democrats, Eileen Daily, precinct 2, prescription drug, RX group, Medicaire, news clippings, action alerts, AARP]
  - Administrative Records, correpsondence, financial records, 1990-2010 (Box 2013.0157_24)
    [subjects include: State of Older Women in America, Voice of Middle and Older Women, Medicaid, Medicare, Education contract, RX, politics, drug company practices, cost factors, AARP, Breaux Frist, tobacco cessation, Alliance for a Healthy Connecticut, cigarette minimum mark up, alliance video press release, Alliance campaigns in other states, email correspondence, prior authorization, Health Budget Cuts 2002, legislative materials, Omnibus Prescription Drug Bill 2000, Reimportation Bill 2000, Medicaid pharmacy cuts Commission on Aging April, 2001, Connecticut Citizens for Nursing Home Reform, social security privatization, Suzanne Haviland, NAIC, Delta Kappa Gamma, Citizens Health Drug Plan, Drug Express to Canada, CCAG, ARA, HCFA lobby day
  - Administrative records, 1990-2010 (Box 2013.0157_25)
    [subjects include: Medicare, Medicaid, Medicaid defense, meetings, FMAP, Mass Health Campaign,RX marketing, Sharon Hospital, discount drugs, healthy Maine prescriptions, prescription drug bill, RX conferences, prescription drug fact sheets, Department of Social Services, 2001 bills, completed health forms, legislator feedback, lobby day, Medicaid Block Granting, sign on letters, testimony, press conferences, Department of the Treasury, RX price discrimination study for the Attorney General, Medigap and rate setting hearing, HB 5639, Husky 2002 legislation, lobby day, transfer of asset waiver, RX bills and testimony]
  - Administrative Records, legal documents, news clippings, 1990-2010 (Box 2013.0157_26)
    [subjects include: 2003 health care bils and testimony, federal PBOR 2001, patients bill of rights, PCCM HB 5607, SB 934, P.A.L. project and lawsuit, special session June-July, 2002, prescription drugs, prescription access litigation, State RX legislation, statements from Senior Groups, ConnPACE, RX legislation from other states, news clippings]
  - administrative files, publications, 1990-2010 (Box 2013.0157_27)
    [subjects include: HCFA, CONNPIRG, Connecticut health notesNational Committee to Preserve Medicare and Social Security, CADH, Capital Region Conference of Churches, Hartford Environmental Justice Network, Connecticut Community Providers Association, Connecticut Society of Nurse Psychotherapists, ConnectiCOSH, HCFA Coalition, Working Families Party, employers, CWMC Memberships, Mental Health Association, SEIU, staffing, Universal Healthcare for Connecticut, Health Care]
  - Administrative Records, news clippings, publications, 1990-2010 (Box 2013.0157_28)
    [subjects include: CEO, Fair Share, Parrella, MMC Coalition Alternatives Coalition, NECARC Grant Training, program staff 1988 payroll, Low-Level Radioactive Waste Management in Connecticut, Threshold, Ipdate, US Nuclear Power Plants Showing Their Age, Draft Low-Level Radioactive Waste Management Report, Congress...We Have A Problem, wealth and poverty, Health Care Press, Wheelabrator, HC/Senate piece, HMO Industry Personnel research, HMO, Health Maintainance Organization, material designs, legislative indexes, factsheets in progress, polling related to democracy, taxes 1985, vacation forms, internships, sexual harassment policies, unions, Connecticut Health Foundation]
  - Administrative records, publications, 1990-2010 (Box 2013.0157_29)
    [subjects include: toxics campaign, Campaign Finance Reform, communications committee, bottle bills, RX, drugs, AARP,RX-drugs reimportation, CCAG Herstory, election laws, election plan 1990, foundation, fundraising - resource materials, Dioxin Regulations, Oil Coop, Oxford, 1984 budget, PFC power campaign, Region 9A UAW, Deerfield, CT, personel issues, LEAP, balanced budget, LEAP finance committee, Southbridge, payments, Anthem, Moira, Dr. Nathan Davis Award, organizing training materials, Public Citizen, Vermont RX Bill 2002, drug legislation, drug discount cards, Share Card, RX price controls, PhRMA, prescription drugs - press releases 1999-2000]